James Mossman Jowett Bradford, West Yorks. jamesmossmanjowett@gmail.com

Mobile 07534 280542

Key Skills:-

Quick "on the job" autodidactic IT skills learner. Logical diagnostic "on the go" problem solving. Proactive self starter.

Cooperative team worker and unsupervised task focused finisher.

Profile:-

35 Years of experience making computers work. building, configuring, networking, upgrading, programming, installing operating systems and applications. Basically, doing what needed to be done, to make things happen. I can't say I'm a guru expert in any one aspect of IT, as there usually isn't time to read the manual from start to finish. I'm a hands on pragmatic problems solver, learning what I need to know, as I work through any problem that needs resolving.

IT Skills:-

Operating Systems:-

Installed, configured, networked and administered the following, predominantly in a business environment. Every version of windows since MSDOS to Windows 10, Windows Server 2008 - 2016. Various flavors of UNIX on PC (Linux), SGI (Irix), Sun (Solaris), Apollo DN(Domain) Hardware. Installed various versions of OS X on MAC hardware.

Programming languages:-

Used to solve real world business problems > Perl, Bash, Python, Powershell, Autolisp, VisualBasic, HTML, Javascript, SQL, Maxscript, Python.

Non commercial > C++, C, Ruby, 386 Assembler, PHP.

System applications and technologies :-

Used to solve real world business problems > Windows Server 2012-2016, Active Directory, DNS, DHCP, Firewalls, Azure Devops, VPN, Apache, Perl DBI, CGI Gateway, MySql, Samba, NFS, RAID, LVM, SMART. Non commercial > Docker, GitHub, Nagios. Jenkins. AWS, puppet.

End User Applications:-

Used to solve real world business problems > Microsoft Outlook /Word /Excel /PowerPoint, Corel Draw, Adobe Premiere & Director, Autocad, 3DStudio MAX, Photoshop, And many minor utility programs.

Hardware Skills:-

Installing motherboards, RAM, CPU, power supplies, hard disks, graphics cards, expansion cards, etc. Rack mounting servers, installing patch panels, running cat5 through buildings wall, floors, ceilings. Making up and terminating CAT5 UTP cable, Installing POE switches and routers. Installing printers, plotters, VoIP phones, NAS and postscript RIPS.

Previous Employment:-

Seafresh, Bradford - Product Manager

June 2019 - Sept. 2019

Advised the director on how Seafresh's bespoke stock control system, running on Windows XP and Foxbase Pro, could be improved. Created reports from the stock control system to measure KPI's on stock variances, barcode errors, stocktakes. Recommended various ways to improve IT security and reliability with regard to e-mailing, CCTV and NAS. Reduce Barcode errors from Approx. 200/day to 20/day. Set up a KPI to measure stocktake variances, then implemented changes that improved stocktake accuracy by 50%.

Bextec, Cleckheaton - IT Support Technician

Sept 2018 - April 2019

Providing IT support to Bextec's various clients. Using Teamviewer to remotely diagnose and solve problems on customers PCs. Installing servers, cat5 cabling, workstations. Administering Office 365, Active Directory, MS Exchange, DNS, DHCP. Migrating clients from on premises servers to Office 365, Sharepoint and OneDrive. Upgrading Windows 7 to Windows 10, Upgrading Office 2010-2013 to Office 365. Integrating VoIP phones onto PC networks.. Wrote software using Python & Powershell to automate SEO tasks using Azure DevOps. Advised clients on various aspects of IT. **Please read reference on last page of CV**

17/4/19 Page 1 of 4

Damart UK, Shipley - Telesale Operator

July 2018 - Sept. 2018

Working in Damarts call centre, helping customers place orders from Damarts postal catalogue.

Part time Freelance IT contractor

April 2006 - Sept. 2017

Freelance IT contractor. Solving Small businesses and private individual IT problems. Setting up computers, websites, networks, printers, etc. The part time aspect of this work was required as I was also caring for my disabled mother.

Three Point Productions, York - Company Director

August 2001 - Feb. 2006

Started up my own company providing IT services to national and multinational construction companies, such as Portakabin, Shepherd Construction, Land Securities Group, McCarthy and Stone and The National Railway Museum. Expanded the business to employ 5 staff.

Shepherd Design, York - IT Support engineer / 3D Visualisation Artist August 1998 – August 2001

IT trouble shooter on network of 70-80 computers running Windows 95,98,NT4,2000. Implemented a database driven intranet app using Linux, Apache, Mysql, PHP and Perl CGI. Configured Samba on Linux to act as 80Gb RAID NAS for CGI render farm. Produced images and animations of proposed buildings using Autocad, 3DStudio Max, Photoshop, Premiere and Director. HTML and JavaScript debugger for DTP department.

David Lyons & Associates, Wakefield - IT Technician / 3D Visualisation Artist April 1995 – June 1998

Administrated, maintained and upgraded a network of 70 computers running NT4/3.51, Windows for workgroups, IRIX, HP-UX, Novell 3.12. Developed several software utilities to enhance Autocad. Setup and looked after e-mail server and created world wide web pages for the Internet. Implemented a basic Intranet. Upgraded coax/Novell network to Cat5 100Mb/s UTP Cable multi-protocol TCP/IP, IPX network. Created 3D computer generated images, photomontage and animations of stadia, arenas and other large-scale projects using Autocad 13, 3D Studio, CorelDraw, Photoshop and Premier. Tutored other members of staff in 3D computer modeling. Provided help desk services for 120 staff.

The Robinson Partnership, Bradford - Architectural Technician

Aug 1994 - Dec 1994

Customised Autocad to produce plan and elevation signage drawings for Shell service stations.

SabreBanner Ltd, Drighlington - Telesales operator selling Unix WorkstationsJuly 1993 - Nov. 1993

Was given the task of trying to sell a warehouse full of 10 year old Apollo DN Workstations, by cold calling Sabre Banners client base.

Bowman Riley Partnership, Skipton - CAD Operator / IT Technician

Feb. 1990 - Dec. 1992

Produced plan, elevation, section and detail drawings for housing and supermarket developments. Created detailed 3D cad models of various projects from individual rooms to complete building sites. Rendered presentation animations using 3D Studio & Animator Pro. Surveyed buildings and drew out the plans in CAD. Customised Autocad to help in the design of ESSO petrol stations using Autolisp to simulate the movement of articulated HGV petrol tankers on service station forecourts. Managed the running of all the cad, word processing and accounting computers. Installed the first network the practice used using tcp/ip.

David Ward Associates, Leeds - CAD Operator / IT Technician April 1989 - Feb. 1990 Created Technical drawings architectural drawings. Administered and maintained 12 PCs.

Group Northern Design, Oulton - CAD Operator / Architectural TechnicianApril 1988 - April 1989

Produced Technical CAD drawings using Autocad and maintained the 20 other PC's the practice used.

Department of Environment, Leeds - Surveyor / CAD Operator July 1987 - Dec. 1987 Leeds College of Building negotiated a short-term 6 month contract student placement.

Leeds College of Building, Leeds - Part time Evening Class TutorSept. 1986 - July 1987

Evening class Tutor. Teaching adults basic computers skills on BBC micros and RM Nimbus PC's

17/4/19 Page 2 of 4

Qualifications:-

Microsoft Learn Portal	Qualification	Grade
	Azure fundamentals (12 Modules)	Pass
	Manage resources in Azure (5 modules)	Pass
Microsoft Virtual Academy	Qualification	Grade
_	Windows Server Fundamentals	Pass
	Powershell for Beginners	Pass
	Understanding Active Directory	Pass
Leeds College of Building	BTEC OND in Building Studies	Pass
Aireville Secondary School	Physics O Level	O level grade B
-	English Language,Chemistry	O Level grade C
	History CSE, Craft & Technology	CSE grade 1
	Metal Work	CSE grade 2
	Maths, Geography, Technical Drawing	CSE grade

3

Online Presence:-

Microsoft Learn Portal :- https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/users/jamesjowett/achievements

LinkedIn:- https://www.linkedin.com/in/james-jowett-96b219152/

Twitter:-@JowettMossman

Facebook:- https://www.facebook.com/profile.php?id=100019441574673

GitHub:- https://github.com/jamesmossmanjowett

Architectural 3D animations :-

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rNV3IKSQgik&list=PLITyAZ9TH5N_nKQGvkwruOPNX9P_0G-dB

Architectural Photomontages :- https://photos.app.goo.gl/arKtgu99dAvr8Kxs9

References:-

- 1) Please read the reference I've included on the last page of this CV.
- 2) Abbey Goater, BridgeIT Housing, 01274 447787

Volunteer Work \ Charity Work:-

BridgeIT Housing - General building maintenance, painting and decorating, gardening, fitting fire doors, building flat pack furniture, furniture and white goods delivery and removals.

17/4/19 Page 3 of 4



Bextec Ltd, Spen Valley House, Rawfolds Industrial Estate, Bradford Road, Cleckheaton, BD19 5LT.

Reference for James Jowett

I am pleased to write this reference for James Jowett. Although James only worked for us for a period of six months, due to unfortunately having to make him redundant, he became a valuable team member. He is reliable and conscientious and has gone over and above what is expected, to ensure customer satisfaction.

James came to us after giving up his own business to care for a relative and needing a chance to get back into employment. He proved to be worth giving an opportunity to as he is hard working and will help in any way he can, using his own business experience and knowledge of IT systems and networks to complete tasks to a good standard.

While working for Bextec Ltd, James' duties have included installing and maintaining networks, servers and desktops and laptops; setting up Standard Operating Procedures forms; ensuring network security; giving customer support through ticketing systems and phone contact as well as setting up Cloud services. He has a good knowledge of Office 365, backup and recovery software, Microsoft Azure, Server 2012 and Windows 7 and 10 Operating Systems.

James has worked closely with our apprentice, teaching him how to complete various tasks related to IT and networks and was both encouraging and patient so would suit a role where he could mentor or lead others. A customer-facing role would also be ideal for James as he has excellent customer service skills being a good balance of friendly and professional even when dealing with adverse situations.

James would be a valuable asset to any company. He will be missed by everyone at Bextec Ltd and I wish him all the best for his future employment. If you have any further questions with regard to his background or qualifications, please do not hesitate to call me.

Yours Faithfully,

Kimberley Green

Operations Director

K.A. am

Bextec Ltd

01274 796108

kimberley.green@bextec.co.uk